遂宁市，二零二二年初中毕业及高中阶段学校招生考试
英语试卷听力部分。
这是遂宁市，二零二二年初中毕业及高中阶段学校招生考试
该部分分为第一、第二两节。
注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将试卷上的答案转涂到客观题。
于答题卡上，请看听力部分第一节。
第一节，听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的
,B I'm not feeling well.
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话读两遍。
现在，你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容。
I have a toothache.
That's too bad.
You should see a I'm not feeling well.
I have a toothache.
That's too bad.
You should see a dentist.
Text 3 Tom, what do you think of sports shows?
I like them, because they're exciting.
Text 4 Jack, can you come to my party this Saturday?
I'd love to, but I'm going going to visit my grandparents.
Jack, can you come to my party this Saturday?
I'd love to, but I'm going to visit my grandparents.
Text 5 I like our English teacher best, because she is humorous.
I think so.
She is great fun.
I like our English teacher best, because she is humorous.
I think so.
She is great fun.
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下面五段对话或独白。
白，每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的
A, B, and and C.
三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
Listen question. Wow, so many hobbies.
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题。
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六、七两个。
小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Every day is quite full for him, right?
Of course. He keeps on running every day.
He also swims three times a week and plays basketball twice a week.
Oh, I see.
Running is his favorite.
That's for sure.
Your father looks young and handsome, Mike.
Thanks. He likes sports a lot, such as running, swimming, and playing basketball.
Wow, so many hobbies.
Every day is quite full for him, right?
Of course. He keeps on running every day.
He also swims three times a week and plays basketball twice a week.
Oh, I see.
Running is his favorite.
That's for sure.
听下面一段对话，回答第八、九两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Wow, that's a real surprise.
Alan, Mother's birthday is coming.
Let's give her a surprise.
Oh yes, I remember it's on June 15th.
What about making a card?
I did that last year.
How about buying some flowers?
No, that's too common.
Mom always does everything for us.
I want to do something special.
Something special?
Cook a meal?
Is it okay?
That's great. I know Mapo tofu is her favorite.
Let's make it.
Wow, that's a real surprise.
听下面一段对话，回答第十。
十二，三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Yes, the biggest one, Xinhua Bookstore, is on Center Street.
Oh, I want to some books.
Would you mind telling me the way?
Of course not.
Go along this street and then turn left on Center Street.
It's on your right, between the post office and the bank.
How long does it take if I walk there?
It's about half an hour, because it's two kilometers away from here.
You need to hurry.
It closes at eight thirty in the evening.
Oh, it's eight o now.
I'll take a taxi.
Thanks a You're welcome.
Excuse me, could you please tell me if there is a bookstore around here?
Yes, the biggest one, Xinhua Bookstore, is on Center Street.
Oh, I want to buy some books.
Would you mind telling me the way?
Of course not.
Go along this street and then turn left on Center Street.
It's on your right, between the post office and the bank.
How long does it take if I walk there?
It's about half an hour, because it's two kilometers away from here.
You need to hurry.
It closes at eight thirty in the evening.
Oh, it's eight o now.
I'll take a taxi.
Thanks a lot.
You're welcome. Text 9.
听下面一段对话，回答第十三至十五三个小题。
现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Congratulations, Tom. You won the first prize in the speech competition.
Thanks a lot.
I remember you used to be very shy in the primary school.
Yes, I used to be afraid of speaking in front of others.
But you have changed a lot.
Yes, after entering the middle school, I joined a storytelling club.
So you changed yourself?
all the students in the club encouraged me.
So I became more and more confident and made much progress.
Good job. I'm proud of you.
Thank you. I will work harder.
Oh, it's time for class.
I have to go now.
Bye. Goodbye, Miss Brown.
Text Tom. You won the first prize in the speech competition.
Thanks a lot.
I remember you used to be very shy in the primary school.
Yes, I used to be afraid of speaking in front of others.
But you have changed a lot.
Yes, after entering the middle school, I joined a storytelling club.
So you changed yourself?
Yeah, all the students in the club encouraged me.
So I became more and more confident and made much progress.
Good job. I'm proud of you.
Thank you. I will work harder.
Oh, it's time for class.
I have to go now.
Bye. Goodbye, Miss Brown.
听下面一段独白，回答第十六至二十五个小题。
现在你有二十五秒钟的时间阅读这五个。
小题。
Text 10. Congratulations, Tom.
You won in competition.
lot. Text 10.
It was sunny last Saturday.
My family went to Kai Ge Farm, which is in countryside of Sui Ning.
It is 46 kilometers away from my home, so we started very early in the morning.
As soon as we arrived, my sister and I picked some fruit with excitement.
My parents took lots of great photos.
My mother couldn't wait to share her happiness with us.
Then all of us watched a Sichuan opera together.
This was my first time to watch it.
I thought it was fantastic.
In the afternoon, we did more interesting things.
Firstly, we went to see some old things of the past.
Secondly, we went to the vegetable garden to see special vegetables that were grown
with high technology.
Thirdly, we learned how to grow flowers from an old farmer.
On the way home, my dad told us the countryside is becoming more and more beautiful,
and we are so lucky to have a happy life.
What a meaningful day!
It was sunny last Saturday.
My family went to Kai Ge Farm, which is in countryside of Sui Ning.
It is 46 kilometers away from my home, so we started very early in the morning.
As soon as we arrived, my sister and I picked some fruit with excitement.
My parents took lots of great photos.
My mother couldn't wait to share her happiness with us.
Then all of us watched a Sichuan opera together.
This was my first time to watch it.
I thought it was fantastic.
In the afternoon, we did more interesting things.
Firstly, we went to see some old things of the past.
Secondly, we went to the vegetable garden to see special vegetables that were grown
with high technology.
Thirdly, we learned how to grow flowers from an old farmer.
On the way home, my dad told us the countryside is becoming more and more beautiful,
and we are so lucky to have a happy life.
What a meaningful day!
a meaningful a Thank you for watching.
第二节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you for watching.
you watching. you you for for Thank watching.
听力部分到此结束。
Thank you